数学形态学的另一种变化
Another variation on mathematical morphology
就是所谓的命中或未命中变换。现在在这种情况下，结构元素
is what's called the hit-or-miss transform. Now in this case, the structuring element
包含具有三个可能值的像素。该值可以为零，这意味着
contains pixels which have three possible values. The value could be zero, which means
它所在的像素必须为零。它可以是一个，这意味着像素
that the pixel that it sits over must be zero. It could be one, which means the pixel that
它坐在上面必须等于一个或它可以有一个值不关心，所以它没有
it sits over must be equal to one or it can have a value of don't care, so it doesn't
无论下面是什么像素值。让我们用一些简单的例子来说明这一点。
matter what pixel value is underneath. Let's illustrate this with some simple examples.
这是两个输入像素模式，我们将覆盖这个特定的命中和未命中
Here are two input pixel patterns, and we're going to overlay this particular hit-and-miss
在每个人的顶部进行转换。现在在第一种情况下，我们看到结果是真的。
transform on top of each of them. Now in the first case, we see that the result is true.
结构元素中的红色像素位于导入图像中的零像素上
The red pixels in the structuring element lay over zero pixels in the import image and
结构元素中的蓝色像素位于输入像素上，所有输入像素都等于1。
blue pixels in the structuring element lay over input pixels which are all equal to one.
结果是真的。我们在这里不关心其他两个像素，它们的价值是什么
So the result is true. We don't care about the other two pixels here, what values they
有，他们不参加。现在让我们来看看这个例子。
have, they do not participate. Now let's have a look at this example.
结构元素中的红色像素位于像素上，在这种情况下不是
The red pixels in the structuring element lay over pixels, which in this case are not
都等于零。结构化元素中的蓝色像素位于输入像素上
all equal to zero. The blue pixels in the structuring element lay over input pixels
这都是一个，所以这很好。但在这种情况下，结果是错误的，因为
which are all one, so that's good. But in this case, the result is false because of
这一个重要的输入像素在这里。可以使用命中和未命中变换
this one valued input pixel over here. The hit-and-miss transform can be used for
许多非常有用和有趣的应用程序。在这里考虑这个输入图像，它是合成的
a lot of really useful and interesting applications. Consider this input image here, it's a synthetic
我使用位图编辑器创建的图像，但我们可以将其视为天线
image that I created using a bitmap editor, but we could think of it perhaps as an aerial
道路网络的照片或类似的东西。现在，通过应用特定序列
photograph of a road network or something like that. Now, by applying a particular sequence
一次又一次地进行“一次又一次”的转换，可以执行一个名为的操作
of hit-and-miss transforms over and over again, it's possible to perform an operation called
骨架。我们所做的就是转换包含数字的输入图像
skeletonization. And what we've done is to convert our input image which contains a number
任意厚度的线条成为该图像的骨架。
of lines of arbitrary thickness into a skeleton of that image.
包含许多行，每行保证只有一个像素宽。现在
Contains a number of lines and each line is guaranteed to be only one pixel wide. Now
我们可以使用名为ithin的工具箱函数执行此骨架化操作
we can perform this skeletonization operation using the toolbox function called ithin and
你传入二进制图像。现在这个操作非常慢，因为这个命中注定
you pass into it a binary image. Now this operation is quite slow because this hit-and-miss
变换本身就是相对昂贵的计算和骨架化
transform is relatively expensive to compute in its own right and to do skeletonization
我们必须按顺序一次又一次地对命中图像应用“命中-未命中”变换
we have to apply the hit-and-miss transform over and over again to the image in order
获得骨架。另一个非常有趣的应用
to obtain the skeleton. Another really interesting application of
命中和未命中变换是找到交叉点。所以我们假设我们有骨架化
the hit-and-miss transform is to find intersections. So let's assume that we have the skeletonized
在上一张幻灯片中创建的图，我想找到交点。一个十字路口
figure created in the previous slide and I want to find the intersection points. An intersection
我要定义一个三个线段合在一起的地方
point I'm going to define as a place where three line segments come together at a single
点。在这种情况下，有五个交叉点
point. And in this case, there are five intersection
点。所以我想找到这三个单像素宽线的像素坐标
points. So I want to find the pixel coordinates where these three single pixel wide lines
遇到。我想找到这些交叉点，我们可以再次使用
meet. I want to find these intersections and again we can perform this function using the
命中与转换。在右手图像中，我们看到了五个交叉点
hit-and-miss transform. In the right hand image we see the five intersection points
突出显示，每个都只是一个像素。
highlighted and each of these is just a single pixel.
像素设置在这三个线段相交的坐标处，我们可以计算
The pixel is set at the coordinate where those three line segments meet and we can compute
这个交叉点使用工具箱函数itriplepoint。输入是二进制图像
this intersection using the toolbox function itriplepoint. The input is a binary image
包含单像素宽骨架类型图像。
that contains a single pixel wide skeleton type image.
再一次，这个三点函数的执行速度非常慢，因为命中注定
Once again, this triple point function is quite slow to execute because the hit-and-miss
必须迭代地执行变换，直到只有这几个孤立的像素
transforms have to be executed iteratively until there are only these few isolated pixels
剩余。这是我介绍的合成图像
remaining. Here's the synthetic image that I introduced
之前，它已加载到工作区中。这是六百八百逻辑
to you earlier, it's loaded into the workspace. It’s a six hundred by eight hundred logical
图像所以值为零或一，所以我可以创建一个稀疏版本
image so the values are either zero or one, so I can create a thinned version of this
使用工具箱函数ithin的图像，我传入逻辑图像，它将计算
image using the toolbox function ithin, I pass in the logical image and it will compute
很长一段时间，差不多一分钟，就在这里。
for quite a while, almost a minute, and here it is.
如果我在新窗口中显示。显示细化图像，我们可以放大这个
If I display this in a new window. Display the thinned image, we can zoom in on this
图像显示它确实是一个像素宽。再次放大，我们可以看到它
image to show that it is indeed a single pixel wide. Zoom in again and we can see that it
只是一个像素宽的线。一大堆白色块端对端堆叠。
is just a single pixel wide line. A whole bunch of white blocks stacked end to end.
好吧，解开那一个。现在我可以计算三重点和我
Alright, unzoom that one. Now I can compute the triple points and I
从工具箱和这个函数使用itriplepoint函数做到这一点，我将通过
do that using itriplepoint function from the toolbox and this function and I'm going pass
在稀疏的图像中。这个功能比上一个快得多
in the thinned image. This function's a lot quicker than the last
一。这是结果，所以我将把它放在第一个并显示三重点
one. Here's the result, so I will put that on figure one and display the triple points
并且很难看到，这里只设置了单个像素，如果我可以放大那里
and little hard to see, there are only single pixels are set here and if I can zoom in there's
三重点之一。
one of the triple points.